<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Scrapbook</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/Scrapbook.html</link>
<description>This page will hold my Ethical Scrapbook, chronicling events which have occured in today’s world which affect ethics in technology.</description>
<generator>iWeb 1.1.2</generator>
<image>
<url>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/Scrapbook_files/Picture%203.png</url>
<title>Scrapbook</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/Scrapbook.html</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Huge Victory for Real People as Net Neutrality bill dies</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/7682A6F5-31E4-48E4-BC78-0E59CC8CA5E6.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/7682A6F5-31E4-48E4-BC78-0E59CC8CA5E6.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 17:12:08 -0800</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  The article discusses the recent decision by Congress to stop senator Ted Stevens’ bill regarding Net Neutrality and a multi-tiered internet.  The lawmaking regarding the internet has now be</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>IRS Taxation of Online Game Virtual Assets Inevitable</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/7CE15793-F47C-45B3-B1F8-D0EBE92145E0.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/7CE15793-F47C-45B3-B1F8-D0EBE92145E0.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 4 Dec 2006 17:47:33 -0800</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This article discusses a recent conference held, where academics, lawyers, and scholars met to talk about the fiscal issues involved in social worlds and the virtual income they create.  &#13;&#13;R</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jigsaw Data not a company that follows standards</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/53580D2C-A652-438E-B51C-F82C90E8B005.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/53580D2C-A652-438E-B51C-F82C90E8B005.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 5 Sep 2006 14:07:40 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This posting is an article about the website and company Jigsaw Data.  Based in California, the website works by encouraging users to share their address books, phone lists, business cards, </description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Play Chess on your nearest e-voting machine</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/0F60F67D-2818-4B9D-B4AC-D50430CFD6A1.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/0F60F67D-2818-4B9D-B4AC-D50430CFD6A1.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 5 Oct 2006 13:40:03 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  IT Professionals have hacked one of the voting machines which is used to collect votes in elections for several European countries.  The machine was originally purchased by the Irish governm</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Warner to talk to Google on YouTube rights-paper</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/E6177D1D-133E-4346-ABC2-AB253A474522.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/E6177D1D-133E-4346-ABC2-AB253A474522.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 12:45:30 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  Time Warner media has just opened talks with Google regarding the use of copyrighted information on the YouTube website.  Until now, YouTube has been piecemeal with the deletion of copyright</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spamhaus to Ignore $11.7 million Judgement</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/2B51C5FA-63A3-491A-A0AD-09ED54FD9E30.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/2B51C5FA-63A3-491A-A0AD-09ED54FD9E30.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 12:22:24 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This article post discusses the situation concerning Spamhaus, a European spam-prevention site.   Spamhaus was ruled by the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of Illinois to pay o</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google CEO: Techies must educate governments</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/498E01D2-0144-4A8E-801E-08DBFAFE829F.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/498E01D2-0144-4A8E-801E-08DBFAFE829F.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2006 12:01:09 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This article discusses a recent public symposium on computer science and telecommunications, specifically net neutrality and spreading the word to the masses.  One of the key speakers at the</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Poll:  Americans Don’t Want Net Neutrality (or maybe they don’t know what it is)</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/3965EB1A-CE7A-436A-A342-DD755E4EC876.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/3965EB1A-CE7A-436A-A342-DD755E4EC876.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2006 11:25:32 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This article discusses two things;  It first addresses the severe lack of Americans who understand what Net Neutrality is, and, it looks at poll data reporting that Americans would vote “no”</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Retains ICANN oversight</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/473204E3-3B78-48ED-889F-52902C2C034C.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/473204E3-3B78-48ED-889F-52902C2C034C.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2006 10:45:34 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This article discusses the decision of the United States to continue to oversee ICANN for at least 18 months, and possibly for up to three more years.  ICANN is the nonprofit organization wh</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Internet Black Hole That Is North Korea</title>
<link>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/09DD7A45-375C-459D-BFCD-0D519FA749A8.html</link>
<guid>http://www.techotter.com/CST373/Scrapbook/09DD7A45-375C-459D-BFCD-0D519FA749A8.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 14:35:43 -0700</pubDate>
<description>Summary:  This article discusses the complete lack of Internet in the country of North Korea.  The government bans most forms of free communication, and internet is nonexistant in the country.&#13;&#13;Reason</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
