<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Journals</title>
    <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals</link>
    <description></description>
    <item>
      <title>Journal 6</title>
      <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/5/1_Journal_6.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b47ccb64-a5c8-455b-a24b-cd85b6432fc7</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 1 May 2008 22:11:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>What did you do at your site this week?&lt;br/&gt;This week at RISE, I was working with the students on using the internet to research the PSATs and SATs. We used the College Board site to research the cost of the tests, what kind of problems were asked, and how to apply to take them.  In addition, we helped to set students up on the College Board website, as well as creating email addresses for those children who did not have them already.  In addition, I have given Bobby a final draft of the new RISE brochures, updated with a new design and more recent photography, for final approval.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2. Goals (did you achieve what you set out to do? If not, explain why not.&lt;br/&gt;I would say that I definitely was able to get out and do the goals which I had laid out for myself at the beginning of the semester.  I worked with the students in RISE, to teach them about computers and the internet, and to impact their lives and futures.  In addition, I was able to use my computer and design skills learned at CSUMB, to help the RISE staff with their brochures and publishing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Best &amp;amp; Worst: Identify what was the best and worst parts of your service&lt;br/&gt;The best parts of my service with RISE were the days where we were able to take students into the tech lab, and have them work on the computers.  This is my natural environment, so I was able to make an impact on the students, and to gain their trust in me as an educator by showing them that I had things that I could teach them.  On the other hand, the worst times were the days when our coursework had nothing to do with technology.  Often, on science days, I would be stuck walking around the classroom monitoring students, with no real work to do;  however, RISE is not a program which caters unilaterally to technology, so this is understandable.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Suggestions (Suggest how service at this site could be better. &lt;br/&gt;RISE has a great program put together, and the Boys &amp;amp; Girls Club in Seaside is an amazing site, with new state of the art education and technology resources.  The only way I think that this site could be better, would be if RISE developed a little more of a framework for how to handle service members, and have tasks which they could be assigned to helping with;  sometimes it seemed like there was a lack of anything for me to do at my site.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;5. Advice: Write your advice to the next Tech Tutor.&lt;br/&gt;My best advice I could give to a future Tech Tutor is this:  to build students&#x2019; trust in you, or anyones trust, for that matter, you have to show them that you have positive input for them.  With students, you must show them that you are, in fact, a teacher, not a student - that you are here to show them things, to educate them. Once they have seen that you have the ability to show them new things, they will put new trust and respect into you, and it will be easier for you to teach them.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/167384766.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment link="http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/5/1_Journal_6.html#comment_layer" count="0" enabled="0"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journal 5</title>
      <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/4/13_Journal_5.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">cbadf956-fca0-4647-a33b-9e21ec2ff6f3</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 22:11:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>What did you do at your site this week?&lt;br/&gt;This week consisted of two separate sessions, again.  At my service site, I helped student with their homework, specifically researching papers on the computer and using the internet to help find scholarly sources.  Back at RISE headquarters, I sent emails back and forth to Bobby, revising the flyer design.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.  Explain what has changed since you started? People? Technology? You?&lt;br/&gt;My ability to educate the students at my service site has become much easier while I have been working at my site.  At first, I was not sure what level the students were at, what they were interested in, where they needed assistance;  now that I have had time to get to know them, I am able to inspire and educate them much more effectively.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Are you on schedule? &lt;br/&gt;Everything is still on schedule - I am about to complete my 30th hour of service with RISE next week, and both the technology education plan and the RISE flyers are on schedule.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Has this turned out as you expected? Are you disappointed, happy, or surprised? Is your supervisor doing what they promised?   What&#x2019;s DIFFERENT? I want to hear about it.&lt;br/&gt;I was very happy with the results of the Tech Tutors program, especially my service site.  RISE, and the Seaside Boys &amp;amp; Girls Club, have been great organizations to work with, and the students that I have worked with over the past semesters are great examples of the students which technology can reach out to and helped the most.  In the end, working with RISE has not only met, but exceeded my expectations of what we can do with technology in education today.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;5. What will you do next week? &lt;br/&gt;Next week, we will be finalizing the designs of the RISE brochure for a printed draft.  Once we see the draft, we can show it to the other staff at RISE for client feedback, so I can make any final changes needed before the end of the semester.  At my service site, we will be reviewing ocean cycles, and looking up information about it on the site computers.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/2205965595.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment link="http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/4/13_Journal_5.html#comment_layer" count="0" enabled="0"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journal 4</title>
      <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/3/31_Journal_.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6286f866-3a2e-4ebf-959a-79a137c83bd0</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 22:11:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>What did you do at your site this week?&lt;br/&gt;This week, I had two separate sessions with my site;  the first was a regular session with the students, using the computers to research new projects and field trips.  The second part, was a visit to the RISE offices, to start looking at the design of the RISE brochure, and making changes and improvements to reflect the vision that RISE is trying to put forward.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2.  Explain what has changed since you started? People? Technology? You?&lt;br/&gt;My view of the RISE program, the difference it makes and the way technology changes students, has changed since the beginning of the program.  At first, I based my own childhood experiences in educational programs; however, when i started to look at those experiences in retrospective, I realized that the times I learned the most were the times where I had been able to educate myself THROUGH my interests, something I had not realized at the time.  What the job of technology in education must be, then, is to show students that learning can be fun, and that learning can be applied to whatever adolescents want to do.  It is not about bringing technology to the children, it is about bringing children to the technology.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Are you on schedule? &lt;br/&gt;Yes, everything is on schedule as far as my work with RISE.  We have begun on the brochure and image redesign, and we are on track to get all the work they need done by the end of the semester. In addition, I am already near completion for my 30 hours of service.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Has this turned out as you expected? Are you disappointed, happy, or surprised? Is your supervisor doing what they promised?   What&#x2019;s DIFFERENT? I want to hear about it.&lt;br/&gt;I was very happy with the results of the Tech Tutors program, especially my service site.  RISE, and the Seaside Boys &amp;amp; Girls Club, have been great organizations to work with, and the students that I have worked with over the past semesters are great examples of the students which technology can reach out to and helped the most.  In the end, working with RISE has not only met, but exceeded my expectations of what we can do with technology in education today.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;5. What will you do next week? &lt;br/&gt;Next week I will be working with Bobby and producing a first draft of the redesigned RISE brochure.  From there, we will refine the design and expand it to cover any changes which need to be made to the RISE image.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/39328690.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment link="http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/3/31_Journal_.html#comment_layer" count="0" enabled="0"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journal 3</title>
      <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/3/7_Journal_3.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d4ca0b43-aef3-45a0-977c-290546ebe91b</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2008 22:11:23 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>This week at my site (explain what you did)&lt;br/&gt;This week at the site was a lot of one-on-one time with the students.  The RISE faculty gets periodic report cards from the teachers of students participating in the program, so that they can see how their students are doing, and concentrate on their sore spots during tutorial sessions.  In addition, I began talking to Bobby, my supervisor, about the design work I would be doing for the program.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Observations (regarding power relationship. Equity, and or access to technology)&lt;br/&gt;The one on one sessions with the students gave me a chance to get more details than usual on the students personal lives and backgrounds, and how that affects their learning. What struck me as the most surprising was the difference that access to technology makes in todays learning processes.   At first glance, it may seem like children can get access to technology in many places besides their homes, but the issue is peaking childrens&#x2019; interest, and making technology easy for them to access.  Would you rather do a project from the comfort of your home, or would you prefer to be forced to do your work elsewhere? Some students choose not to do their work at all, because they are not encouraged enough, to go out and find resources.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Connections (relate to CSUMB experience)&lt;br/&gt;The CSUMB connection here is the actual connection between CSUMB and the community, through the RISE program.  As I discussed above, the ease of use of technology resources is a huge factor in encouraging adolescence to use technology to their advantage;  it doesn&#x2019;t just have to be available to them, they have to WANT to use these resources.  The RISE program, is essentially a way to get students more interested in learning, and by helping the program with technology integration, I am helping these students become more interested in science and technology.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Previous Experiences (relate past experiences to now)&lt;br/&gt;When I first started working with the RISE program, it was obvious, in my opinion, to tell those who were truly interested in science and technology, apart from those who were just there because they were forced to be.  However, as I have worked with students more, I have discovered that for some, that interest just lies dormant in their personalities, waiting to be awakened.  It is up to us as educators, to bring out the interests of these students, so they can figure out what their passions are, and who they will become.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Perceptions (reinforced or challenged your perceptions)&lt;br/&gt;The experience mentioned above, to figure out children&#x2019;s passions, has been reinforced by experiences I have had with these students in the past few weeks. Bobby, my supervisor, is a great educator, and I have seen students who at first expressed no interest in the program, now anxious to participate in labs and field trips.  Even if a student turns out not to be interested in a certain topic, it was worthwhile to check; perhaps they will like the next topic more.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Next week (your plans to better serve or connect to people at your site)&lt;br/&gt;Next week I have double meetings with RISE; one is my normal participation session with the students at the Boys and Girls club;  in addition, on Friday, I will be meeting with the RISE staff, to discuss improvements to their flyers and image, and I will be collecting photos and previous resources, to help RISE design a new brochure for themselves.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/511787344.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment link="http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/3/7_Journal_3.html#comment_layer" count="0" enabled="0"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journal 2</title>
      <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/2/18_Journal_2.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">bb210d25-0989-4c32-bfef-a3b522f793ac</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 22:11:21 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>RISE @ Seaside Boys &amp;amp; Girls Club&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This week at my site (explain what you did)&lt;br/&gt;This week at my site, we went over a few field trips that were going to be happening with the students, one of the larger ones being the CSUMB Science Day coming up this weekend.  After that, we went over what the students were learning in their science classes (tide pools and biology), and then I helped tutor a few of the students.  In addition, I briefly talked with Bobby about the upcoming design work I will be doing for the club.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Observations (regarding power relationship. Equity, and or access to technology)&lt;br/&gt;Field trips are a large part of the RISE experience;  they draw the students in, the lure of getting to go explore new places, and at the same time they can teach the students more about the world.  We are going on several field trips this semester, and the first one is this weekend, to CSUMB no less.  The science department has a high school science day, so we will be bringing the students to that.  New ways to teach are what keeps students interested in your material.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Connections (relate to CSUMB experience)&lt;br/&gt;This week, the CSUMB connection is shown by the upcoming Science Day at the university.  This is just one example, along with the service learning program, of how CSUMB gives back to the community and helps it improve as a whole.  My entire stay at CSUMB has been summarized by respect and knowledge about all peoples and cultures, and nowhere else is this apparent more than through the communities and peoples which CSUMB reaches out to to assist in the community.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Previous Experiences (relate past experiences to now)&lt;br/&gt;It seems like as the students at RISE become more accustomed to me helping in their classes, the more trust they put into me, and the more comfortable they feel asking me for help with their classes.  As I have put more time into the RISE program, I have also learned more about the students and the goals of the program, and have become more interested in supporting the goals of RISE and the Seaside BGC.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Perceptions (reinforced or challenged your perceptions)&lt;br/&gt;Its interesting to note the different challenges that boys and girls have in high school.  Boys, in the RISE program, seem to be much more concentrated on their social standing, impressing their friends, and goofing around during sessions;  girls, while also largely social at this age, have much more of a hold on their work, and tend to take more out of the program than boys do.  The question is, how can we alter our teaching fashions so that both boys and girls get the most out of the RISE program?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Next week (your plans to better serve or connect to people at your site)&lt;br/&gt;Next week, I plan to continue working with the students at the site, and continue talking to Bobby about what the RISE program is looking to put into their flyers and promotional information.  Hopefully, with the information he gives me, I can begin to brainstorm and create some outlines of the media that RISE wants me to create for them.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/471910816.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment link="http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/2/18_Journal_2.html#comment_layer" count="0" enabled="0"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journal 1</title>
      <link>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/2/11_Journal_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8eb60f3a-3f3c-4b32-ae63-d20a07769606</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 22:09:16 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>RISE @ Seaside Boys &amp;amp; Girls Club&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This week at my site (explain what you did)&lt;br/&gt;This week at my site, I was able to take a look at the students progress with computers and math skills, as well as a feel for what kind of computer tutoring we were looking at doing in the next few weeks.  We worked with simple college research, which gave me a good idea of the students&#x2019; skills with the computers. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Observations (regarding power relationship. Equity, and or access to technology)&lt;br/&gt;It&#x2019;s a great feeling to see these students so enthused when they are using the internet, especially when it is doing something for their own good like college research.  It is so hard for many of the students to get a computer at all, much less broadband internet access, and so for many of them the club is a valuable resource, a link to what all of us at CSUMB are working for.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Connections (relate to CSUMB experience)&lt;br/&gt;Working with this class really helps me to see the extent that the CSUMB vision statement extends, to helping the under-represented gain their education and success.  This idea extends far beyond CSUMB;  through Service Learning, RISE, and other school programs, CSUMB&#x2019;s vision extends to the entire community, helping even these students who are barely considering colleges yet.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Previous Experiences (relate past experiences to now)&lt;br/&gt;Working at the Boys and Girls Club is a unique experience for me, since this will be my second semester working there - I helped out in lower division service learning last semester.  Because of this, I have gotten a unique perspective into the relationships of the students and teachers as the year progresses.  When the year starts, students are weary of their teachers, testing the waters to see what the instructor will tolerate. However, by now in the second semester, the atmosphere is much more relaxed, and the students and instructors are much more at ease with each other.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Perceptions (reinforced or challenged your perceptions)&lt;br/&gt;I would say that so far, my perceptions have gradually been changed throughout the course of my service at the RISE site.  At first, I was not sure that all of the students would participate in the program;  some seemed like &#x201C;rebel types&#x201D; - but all of the students really have an honest interest in science and technology, and I&#x2019;m really looking forward to developing a lesson plan which will introduce them more fully to the internet and how to use it best.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Next week (your plans to better serve or connect to people at your site)&lt;br/&gt;Next week, I plan to continue working with the students at the site, to get an idea of what kind of information I should put into the website and media regarding the students and program at the Boys and Girls Club.  In addition, I will be helping the RISE students prepare for a &#x201C;Science Day&#x201D; which is occuring on the CSUMB campus later this month.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/images3Fq3Dnumber2Bone26svnum3D1026um3D126hl3Den26sa3DN.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment link="http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals/Entries/2008/2/11_Journal_1.html#comment_layer" count="0" enabled="0"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <iweb:dateFormat>EEEE, MMMM d, yyyy</iweb:dateFormat>
    <iweb:baseURL>http://www.webrender.net/CST361/Journals</iweb:baseURL>
    <iweb:maximumSummaryItems>18</iweb:maximumSummaryItems>
  </channel>
</rss>
